MARK OKAFOR, MS

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | DATA SCIENTIST | MACHINE LEARNING

ABOUT ME

Nashville based Software Developer/Data Scientist with experience in Healthcare IT and Education currently pursuing a PhD in Information Technology. Technical skills include MERN stack, NextJS, NestJS, .NET Core, GraphQL, Databases (MongoDB, MySQL, POSTgres, SQLite), Python (Numpy, MATPLOTLIB, Seaborn, Pandas) and Java. Experience with machine Learning tools including Scikit-learn, Tensorflow and learners.

[] 615 - 918 - 146	C
----------------------------	---

daformark@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/okaformark

www.github.com/okaformark

EDUCATION

Doctorate Degree in Information Technology

January 2023 - Present

- University of the Cumberland
- Florence, KY

Masters Degree in Computer Science

August 2020 - December 2022

- Tennessee State University
- Nashville, TN

Certificate in Software Development

February 2019 - February 2020

- Nashville Software School
- Nashville, TN

Masters Degree in Environmental Science

August 2020 - December 2017

- Tennessee State University
- Nashville, TN

Bachelors of Engineering in Agric & Bio-resources Engr.

August 2005 - August 2010

- University of Nigeria, Nsukka
- Enugu, Nigeria

SKILLS

- Front-end Development
- Back-end Development
- Database Design / Modelling
- Data Analysis / Visualization
- Data Science / Machine Learning
- Healthcare IT / eCW / HL7

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Freelance

Nashville, TN April, 2021 - Present

- Created a fantasy sports app using NextJS, TypeScript, GraphQL, and TailwindCSS based on Figma designs.
- Improved systems through testing, code refactoring, and debugging in Node/Express JS, and REST API's.
- Assessed client requirements and designed systems to meet technical specifications.

Application Developer Intern

Brentwood, TN May 2021 - August 2021

HCA HealthCare - Physician Services Group

- Worked with HCA IT leadership to develop a web application using C# and ASP.NET CORE razor pages, incorporating dynamic behavior through the use of JavaScript and jQuery.
- Managed and configured interface definitions for mapping electronic health records from HL7 standards to eCW fields.
- Managed database object definitions in a SQL server database project

Research Associate & Graduate Assistant

Nashville, TN

Tennessee State University

August 2020 - December 2022 August 2015 - December 2017

- Retrieved and stored data from MS Excel sheets.
- Data analysis and visualization using MS Excel on survey results obtained from Qualtrics.
- Developed survey questionnaires for use on Qualtrics.
- Research associate at the remote sensing lab
- Collected and analyzed water samples for physical and chemical parameters in a wetland, using SPSS, Excel, and Word for data interpretation.
- Installed a multi-parameter sonde data logger in wetland to measure water quality.
- Performed reviews of scientific research papers through studying literature.